<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ajax and Web API on COMP312 labs</title>
    <link>http://philiplei.github.io/webapi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ajax and Web API on COMP312 labs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 08:36:00 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://philiplei.github.io/webapi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>5-1 Designing a Web API</title>
      <link>http://philiplei.github.io/webapi/5-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 08:23:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://philiplei.github.io/webapi/5-1/</guid>
      <description>In an Ajax web app, the application server implements a Web API that provides service to the front-end JavaScript code.
A Web API is a defined set of HTTP request messages along with a definition of the structure of response messages, usually expressed in an XML or JSON format (from Wikipedia).
RPC-style Web API A common design style of Web API is RPC-style (Remote Procedure Call). A RPC-style Web API allocates one URL for each function or operation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5-2 Implementing a Web API</title>
      <link>http://philiplei.github.io/webapi/5-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2016 13:43:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://philiplei.github.io/webapi/5-2/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss implementation of the Web API in last section using Express framework.
Endpoints with GET method This section discusses the implementation of two endpoints of the Web API. Both are read-only and use GET method. They return the result in JSON data format.
   method URL function     GET /getTodo List all tasks   GET /searchTodo Search tasks that are due before the given date.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5-3 Consuming a Web API</title>
      <link>http://philiplei.github.io/webapi/5-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2016 08:43:00 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://philiplei.github.io/webapi/5-3/</guid>
      <description>In this lab, we&amp;rsquo;ll write client-side JavaScript to consume a Web API. We&amp;rsquo;ll use jQuery library to send GET and POST requests to the Web API.
Endpoints with GET method There are two endpoints with GET method in our sample app.
   method URL function     GET /getTodo List all tasks   GET /searchTodo Search tasks that are due before the given date.    In jQuery, the basic method to send Ajax call with GET method is $.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>